<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-13T09:49:18+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Dalwhinnie past bedtime</title><subtitle>Here we are. Dalwhinnie past bedtime. Just need to get this working.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Permanence</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/13/permanence.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Permanence" /><published>2018-01-13T09:45:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-13T09:45:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/13/permanence</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/13/permanence.html"></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Just this</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/11/just-this.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Just this" /><published>2018-01-11T23:13:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-11T23:13:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/11/just-this</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/11/just-this.html">&lt;p&gt;Just this, then bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been sleeping irregularly lately. Waking up too early at best, in the middle of the night at worst. A past girlfriend would’ve told me I’ve been ‘activated’. Myself, I blame it on stress. Self-induced stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started with last year’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andersblehr/MyAoC&quot;&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt;. A colleague mentioned it, said I should give it a go. So I did, half-heartedly – and got hooked. There’s no crack of dawn during winter in Norway, just darkness, but I was up all the same, eagerly awaiting the day’s puzzles, not finding rest until they were done. I relished the challenges, to use my brain for something &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; for a change (although really, it wasn’t &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; real), instead of just generating &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;if&lt;/code&gt;s and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;else&lt;/code&gt;s for a living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Christmas came and went, and with it the puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my brain kept spinning. I stumbled across &lt;a href=&quot;http://exercism.io&quot;&gt;exercism&lt;/a&gt; and installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rust_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;. I want to learn Rust. But I also want to pick up Lisp again, and Prolog and Smalltalk, all of which I made acquaintance with during my studies a quarter of a century ago, but never since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I dug out the old code snippets that had been languishing in Dropbox and decided they needed a promotion. To GitHub, no less. But how? To each snippet its own repository seemed like total overkill. Then I came across &lt;a href=&quot;http://kvz.io&quot;&gt;kvz&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://kvz.io/blog/2014/02/21/how-to-deprecate-projects-on-github/&quot;&gt;depreciation hack&lt;/a&gt;, and apart from the fact that I’m not at all ashamed of my old code, it was a perfect fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So since yesterday, there it is, my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andersblehr/Scrapbook&quot;&gt;scrapbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now this. This site has held nothing but a static ‘Hello World’ &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; file for almost a year. I wanted to do more, but despite my 25 years in the business, I had never done web development. Yes, irrational though it may sound, web development intimidated me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as fate would have it, I interviewed for an iOS gig, got it, and then priorities shifted and they tossed Smarty, Laravel and Ionic at me instead. It’s been over 6 months now, and the hairy mess that is HTML/CSS/JavaScript is much less messy in my head now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There may be more. But now bed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Just this, then bed.</summary></entry></feed>